<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>~finlay</title>
        <description></description>      
        <link></link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2017</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Testing publishling 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 15:29:30 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2017/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2017/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2016</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Get-Jiro-Anthony-Bourdain/dp/1401228283/&quot;&gt;Get Jiro!&lt;/a&gt;, by Anthony Bourdain (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Fun and trivial, a dystopian future where chefs rule the world. Lots of familiar themes from Bourdain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/OISHINBO-JAPANESE-CUISINE-Tetsu-Kariya/dp/1421521393/&quot;&gt;Oishinbo, Volume 1 - Japanese Cuisine&lt;/a&gt;, by Tetsu Kariya (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Now I know how to eat nori.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Oishinbo-Carte-Vol-Ramen-Gyoza/dp/1421521415/&quot;&gt;Oishinbo, Volume 3 - Ramen and Gyoza&lt;/a&gt;, by Tetsu Kariya (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Weaker than the previous ones. And some of the translations felt like they were done by a high-schooler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/UI-Communication-Intuitive-Interfaces-Effective/dp/0123969808/&quot;&gt;UI is Communication&lt;/a&gt;, by Everett N. McKay (5/5)&lt;br&gt;
Just framing the UI, and the design process, as a conversation suddenly makes so many things obvious and easier. I couldn&amp;#39;t articulate before why certain UIs really frustrated me, but they were conversations with annoying, pedantic, forgetful people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Oishinbo-Carte-Vol-Sushi-Sashimi/dp/1421521423/&quot;&gt;Oishinbo, Volume 4 - Fish, Sushi and Sashimi&lt;/a&gt;, by Tetsu Kariya (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Better than the ramen edition, I think. Have to see which of these fish are available locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Chinese-Breeze-300-word-Graded-Reader/dp/7301141556/&quot;&gt;你最喜欢谁? Whom Do You Like More?&lt;/a&gt;, by Yuehua Liu (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
Very basic story, but not too repetitive. Includes recorded readings (normal and slow speed) which really help practicing to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Oishinbo-%C3%A0-Carte-Vol-Sake/dp/1421521407/&quot;&gt;Oishinbo, Volume 2 - Sake&lt;/a&gt;，by Tetsu Kariya (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
A bit more detailed information than some of the other volumes? Still, these have such a repetitive format, it&amp;#39;s hard to stay interested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Praise-Shadows-Junichiro-Tanizaki/dp/0918172020/&quot;&gt;In Praise of Shadows&lt;/a&gt;, by Jun&amp;#39;ichirō Tanizaki (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
&amp;quot;Westerners are amazed at the simplicity of Japanese rooms, perceiving them no more than ashen walls bereft of ornament. Their reaction is understandable, but it betrays a failure to comprehend the mystery of shadows.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/MetaHack-Interviews-Ted-Chiang-ebook/dp/B00AGU3HMC/&quot;&gt;The MetaHack Interviews&lt;/a&gt;, by Avi Solomon (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
Came for the interview with Ted Chiang, stayed for the other interesting bits that sent me off searching for more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/So-Me-Graham-Norton/dp/0340833491/&quot;&gt;So Me&lt;/a&gt;, by Graham Norton (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
My favourite talk show. Can only read it in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fluent-Forever-Learn-Language-Forget/dp/0385348118/&quot;&gt;Fluent Forever&lt;/a&gt;, by Gabriel Wyner (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
Some really good tips, especially the focus on learning the sound-system, which is almost never taught effectively. Mostly focuses on how to create and use flashcards. Read Paul Nation&amp;#39;s &amp;quot;What do you need to know to learn a foreign language&amp;quot; for a broader overview (e.g., tasks for input vs developing fluency).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Children-Seeking-Bridge-Chinese-Breeze/dp/7301079214/&quot;&gt;连个想上天的孩子 Two Children Seeking the Joy Bridge&lt;/a&gt;, by Yuehua Liu (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
Another good graded reader, great for increasing reading fluency. My minor irritation with this series is that the footnote numbers for new vocabulary often split a two-character word or compound, making it harder (as a beginner) to recognize them as a single unit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ex-formation-Kenya-Hara/dp/3037784660/&quot;&gt;Ex-Formation&lt;/a&gt;, by Kenya Hara (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
My favourites were the solid smoke shapes, and the bottles-as-bodies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Teamwork-Individual-Skill-Getting-Responsibility/dp/1576751554/&quot;&gt;Teamwork Is an Individual Skill&lt;/a&gt;, by Christopher Avery (4/5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fire-Upon-Deep-Zones-Thought/dp/0812515285/&quot;&gt;A Fire Upon the Deep&lt;/a&gt;, by Vernor Vinge (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Sci-fi meets fantasy? I liked the whole premise of the zones, and some of the hard sci-fi, but the softer bits were pretty weak and not really compelling. Probably won&amp;#39;t read #2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Tetris-Games-People-Box-Brown/dp/162672315X/&quot;&gt;Tetris: The Games People Play&lt;/a&gt;, by Box Brown (3/5)&lt;br&gt;
Fun, quick history of a perfect game. Read &amp;#39;The Making of Prince of Persia&amp;#39; if you&amp;#39;re interested in a developer view of this era of programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Zone-Win-Organizing-Compete-Disruption/dp/1682302113/&quot;&gt;Zone to Win&lt;/a&gt;, by Geoffrey A. Moore (4/5)&lt;br&gt;
It&amp;#39;s a good articulation of a rational strategy that seems to fit the problem. Changing to adopt such a strategy is probably as hard as the original problem. I recommend &amp;#39;Good Strategy, Bad Strategy&amp;#39; as a good compliment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lady-Monk-Four-Seasons-Kyoto/dp/0679738347/&quot;&gt;The Lady and the Monk: Four Seasons in Kyoto&lt;/a&gt;, by Pico Iyer (5/5)&lt;br&gt;
A beautiful exploration of cross-cultural understanding and misunderstanding. Read while in Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 14:57:24 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2016/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2016/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2015</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0446531502/&quot;&gt;The Art of Profitability&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Adrian J. Slywotzky (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Semi-interesting catalog of 23 profit models. But I always find the
&amp;quot;instructive conversation&amp;quot; style in books really contrived and painful. Pair
with &amp;quot;Staying Power&amp;quot;, by Michael Cusumano for another interesting perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0679642609/&quot;&gt;Meditations: A New Translation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Marcus Aurelius (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Re-read 2015. Such a great mixture of notes-to-self, and zen-like observations
of the world. Check out &amp;quot;Only Don&amp;#39;t Know&amp;quot;, (teaching letters to students) by
Seung Sahn for a very complimentary Zen perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1430308001/&quot;&gt;Predator at the Chessboard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ward Farnsworth (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Outstanding. This breaks down the basic tactical themes in a way that just fit
perfectly for me -- whenever I finished a chapter, I would immediately start
to see those ideas popping up in games. I read this online from his website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1931930996/&quot;&gt;Encountering the Chinese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Hu Wenzhong (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
This was a good cultural overview of China. I was aware of all the broad
themes, but I found a number of subtleties that refined my understanding, and
put some previous interactions in a new light. Very useful. Including pinyin
without tone marks is annoying, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/082642788X/&quot;&gt;Let&amp;#39;s Talk About Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Carl Wilson (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
I liked the parts about the socio-economics of &amp;quot;taste&amp;quot;, and signalling of
social and cultural capital. I&amp;#39;ve never been a Céline hater, so I found the
hand-wringing about liking her to be kind of dull.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1422186431/&quot;&gt;Leading Change&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by John P. Kotter (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Great advice on what it will take to achieve change in large, slow-moving
organizations. All of the obstacles and anti-patterns were painfully familiar,
and the advice seems straightforward in retrospect, but isn&amp;#39;t obvious when
you&amp;#39;re in the middle of the problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0674729013/&quot;&gt;Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Peter C. Brown (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
How to learn? You&amp;#39;re probably doing at least some of it wrong (inefficiently).
My two biggest takeaways are: 1) to move on well before you have &amp;quot;mastered&amp;quot;
the material, and instead come back repeatedly to build up your levels, and 2)
that retrieval is what you&amp;#39;re really after, and quizzes are &amp;quot;retrieval
practice&amp;quot;... quiz always.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0262201682/&quot;&gt;Evocative Objects: Things We Think with&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Sherry Turkle (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Great book, with lots of linkages to other people I find interesting (Piaget,
Seymour Papert, Marcel Mauss). Should be nibbled on, don&amp;#39;t overdo it. A couple
of the objects were personally evocative (raincoat hood!), most were
interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1941875033/&quot;&gt;盲人国 (The Country of the Blind)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by H.G. Wells (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
My first &amp;quot;book&amp;quot; read in Chinese... exhausting! Quite well done given the very
limited vocabulary, and the repetition definitely helped my reading speed a
lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0231149913/&quot;&gt;Uncreative Writing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kenneth Goldsmith (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Whatever. Wanted to like this, but it had no substance, and the author got off
on the wrong foot with me by not understanding what a binary file is. Still,
there were a few interesting references like Sol LeWitt&amp;#39;s wall drawings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1941875009/&quot;&gt;秘密花园 (The Secret Garden)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Frances Hodgson Burnett (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Chinese Graded Reader edition. Not much new vocab, but the repetition really
helps my reading speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1941875017/&quot;&gt;卷发公司的案子 (Sherlock Holmes and the Red-Headed League)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Arthur Conan Doyle (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Quick and simple translation of the story. Good practice material for reading
speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0804139024/&quot;&gt;The Martian&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Andy Weir (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Pure hard sci-fi plus survival fantasy. It was OK, but without any
psychological angle to drive it, I got crisis fatigue from one emergency
stacked on top of another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1941875041/&quot;&gt;六十年的梦 (The Sixty Year Dream)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Washington Irving (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Rip Van Winkle in Beijing. This is a graded reader for learning to read 
Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0824827600/&quot;&gt;Ideogram: Chinese Characters and the Myth of Disembodied Meaning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by J. Marshall Unger (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Really interesting, although I wasn&amp;#39;t able to make much sense of the second
half. Favourite part was the comparison to English shorthand rules and
techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0692442901/&quot;&gt;TPRS with Chinese Characteristics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Terry T. Waltz (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
I&amp;#39;m not a teacher -- I read this looking for ideas to help my self-study. To
that end, I didn&amp;#39;t really find much new, as it was all pretty general and I
had seen most things from other sources already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B003VS0MZQ/&quot;&gt;Dave Barry Does Japan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Dave Barry (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Good fun, classic Dave Barry. A bunch of genuine laugh-out-loud moments in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/3037781831/&quot;&gt;White&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kenya Hara (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
I love his designs, but I had trouble getting anything out of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0470624159/&quot;&gt;The Little Book That Still Beats the Market&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Joel Greenblatt (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Very basic idea expanded with a lot of backstory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B0168JS8IC/&quot;&gt;Foundations of Chinese Characters&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kyle Balmer (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Introduction to the structure and system of Chinese writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0982273606/&quot;&gt;Earth Vs. Everybody&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by John Swartzwelder (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Frank Burly is at it again... a zany cartoon, nothing more (and I read it in Mexifo).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0143125427/&quot;&gt;Lexicon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Max Barry (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Fun read. Matrix meets sorcery, kind of an action movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0062224662/&quot;&gt;The Art of Communicating&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Thich Nhat Hanh (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Great reminders. Just be here, now, and listen with compassion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0060555661/&quot;&gt;The Intelligent Investor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Preston Pysh (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
You are probably a defensive investor, now act like one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1400205573/&quot;&gt;Notes from a Blue Bike&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Tsh Oxenreider (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Meh. I judged the book by its cover and I expected more than anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2016 02:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2015/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2015/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2014</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/039332043X/&quot;&gt;The Gift: The Form and Reason for Exchange in Archaic Societies&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Marcel Mauss (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Very interesting essay on the history and function of &amp;quot;gift giving&amp;quot; (gift
almost certainly carries the wrong connotation). Covers the potlatch culture
of West Coast natives, Brahmin society in India, and the origins of Roman and
German law. Fascinating to see how these traditions are retained in
contemporary society, either through explicit laws or implicit cultural
expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0930289234/&quot;&gt;Watchmen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Alan Moore (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A few of my friends consider this to be an amazing work, but I think I just
read it at the wrong time. I remember that feeling of Cold War impending doom
(although I was relatively young), but it&amp;#39;s just too far away to give this
real impact. I do like Alan Moore&amp;#39;s point about Rorschach being an
exploration of what Batman would be in real life (psychopathic).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0141311401/&quot;&gt;Boy: Tales of Childhood&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Roald Dahl (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/006197014X/&quot;&gt;Diagraphics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Macarena San Martin (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Some nice examples of infographics (not analytic visualizations). Lots of
stuff that didn&amp;#39;t appeal to me visually, but there are a few gems in there to
inspire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0878301178/&quot;&gt;Impro&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Keith Johnstone (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
This has been on my list to read for ages... why did I wait so long? It&amp;#39;s
nominally about improvisation for theatre actors, but really it&amp;#39;s as much
about the theatre of life. People play funny games, and behave in ways
mysterious even to themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp//&quot;&gt;Replay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ken Grimwood (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Meh. A fairly predictable run of events, mostly about getting a do-over on
things you regret in life, with an un-surprising conclusion. I breezed through
it on a plane ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1933330236/&quot;&gt;A Tractate on Japanese Aesthetics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Donald Richie (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Turns out seventeenth-century tea masters were the original hipsters,
elevating the old and ordinary to a refined aesthetic (complicated
simplicity). Of course Japan has compartmentalized and codified aesthetics to
an extreme (unique?) level -- this essay also reminds us that these concepts
have complex histories, in which they were redefined and repurposed to suit
elite political and class distinctions. It was an interesting but not
inspiring read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/111846219X/&quot;&gt;Data Points: Visualization That Means Something&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Nathan Yau (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A good, solid, overview of creating meaningful visualizations. There is much
more detail in books like &amp;quot;Grammar of Graphics&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;Semiology of Graphics&amp;quot;, or
any of Tufte&amp;#39;s work, but this one pulls the basics together in one place, with
good looking examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1881052338/&quot;&gt;Patterns of High Performance: Discovering the Ways People Work Best&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Jerry L. Fletcher (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
This book has some interesting reminders about recognizing and working within
your personal best patterns, and the individuality of those patterns. The
format is mostly anecdotal, with case studies from the author&amp;#39;s consulting
practice, so a lot of it is really general coaching observations, and there&amp;#39;s
very little methodology. Still, it made me reflect on my own situations, and
could definitely be a useful trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1853261890/&quot;&gt;The Best Short Stories&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Guy de Maupassant (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Elaborate and unresolved. His style kind of grew on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0393244660/&quot;&gt;Flash Boys: A Wall Street Revolt&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Michael Lewis (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Frightening... but not terribly surprising. Take a bunch of people with a
history of bad behaviour, give them a financial incentive and don&amp;#39;t watch them
closely, and they will behave badly (ie, make off like bandits). Engaging
writing, but it could have been shorter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0446678791/&quot;&gt;Free Agent Nation: The Future of Working for Yourself&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Daniel H. Pink (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Lots of values in here that resonate with me. The book is quite dry, and seems
a little dated (2001) -- it would be interesting to see newer numbers to see
how these trends progressed, especially in light of services like AWS and
Stripe that make it easier than ever to independently serve your stuff to the
world. Feels like a bit of a companion to The Cluetrain Manifesto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp//&quot;&gt;The Emperor&amp;#39;s River: Travels to the Heart of a Resurgent China&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Liam James D&amp;#39;Arcy-Brown (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Interesting topic, but not a very engaging read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1583941150/&quot;&gt;Body and Mature Behavior: A Study of Anxiety, Sex, Gravitation, and Learning&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Moshé Feldenkrais (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A holistic view of body and mind, layering of the nervous system, and patterns
of development. I don&amp;#39;t know if his theories are strictly correct, but they&amp;#39;re
quite interesting and thought-provoking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0974551627/&quot;&gt;Marching Bands Are Just Homeless Orchestras&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Tim Siedell (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Tweets in a book. Some hilarious one-liners in here. Very short. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0393310728/&quot;&gt;How to Lie with Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Darrell Huff (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
A classic. I think people are a little more aware of &amp;quot;correlation-causation&amp;quot;,
etc, these days, but the warnings about unqualified averages, percentages,
general charting trickery are timeless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0916636003/&quot;&gt;Language Acquisition Made Practical&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by E. Thomas Brewster (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
A very detailed framework for building your own language study plan. It was
originally written for people learning a language where there was no pre-
existing material (eg, making recordings, etc), while these days you probably
already have access to lots of high-quality audio. But it&amp;#39;s still important to
understand a structure and set of techniques -- your Pimsleur or Assimil
course will get you started, but you really have to take ownership of the
process if you want to reach a higher level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1607740087/&quot;&gt;Artisan Cheese Making at Home&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Mary Karlin (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Gorgeous pictures, home-sized recipes, and lots of information on tools, cultures, etc. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1449335586/&quot;&gt;Scope and Closures (You Don&amp;#39;t Know JS)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kyle Simpson (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Brief and extremely clear explanation. Some good points (eg, details of
function hoisting) that I hadn&amp;#39;t tripped over before, but am glad to know now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B00MT612SC/&quot;&gt;Observations of a Straight White Male with No Interesting Fetishes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Peter Hunt Welch (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Amusing and quick. Sort of reminds me of Chuck Klosterman. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1451665067/&quot;&gt;Happy Money: The Science of Smarter Spending&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Elizabeth Dunn (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Some interesting points, but it felt like it could be half the length. Just
full of &amp;quot;Studies show...&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;Researchers asked students...&amp;quot; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1491904151/&quot;&gt;This &amp;amp; Object Prototypes (You Don&amp;#39;t Know JS)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kyle Simpson (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Another solid review of the internals of JS. All devs should probably read this,
if only to drive the idea out of their heads that OO and inheritance are somehow
intrinsic to software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0804139296/&quot;&gt;Zero to One: Notes on Startups, or How to Build the Future&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Peter Thiel (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A clarion call to Definite Optimism... build the Better Future, starting now. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0307739791/&quot;&gt;十個詞彙裡的中國 (China in Ten Words)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Yu Hua (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. The tragedy of the
Cultural Revolution, followed by the rebound into economic explosion (but with
incredible disparity inside the country). A very interesting perspective on
contemporary Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B003Y3BB9O/&quot;&gt;Dreaming in Chinese&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Deborah Fallows (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A fun and very light (after reading &amp;#39;China in Ten Words&amp;#39;) take on aspects of
Chinese culture, via the use, structure, and idioms of the language. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0307387569/&quot;&gt;The Man Within My Head&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Pico Iyer (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
I&amp;#39;m a big fan of Graham Greene, and this gave me lots of new perspectives on
him, and will make me go back to reread some books. Overall, this one started
strong and interesting, but went adrift in the middle (uncertain structure),
then finished reasonably well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 02:35:00 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2014/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2014/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Wallpaper</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Some tiling backgrounds that I drew after looking at pictures of vintage wallpaper. Code is at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/findango/Wallpaper&quot;&gt;https://github.com/findango/Wallpaper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flowers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2 medium-block-grid-3&quot;&gt; &lt;li&gt; &lt;a class=&quot;th&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;flowers.png&quot;&gt;  &lt;img src=&quot;flowers.png&quot;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Starlite&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2 medium-block-grid-3&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;a class=&quot;th&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;starlite.png&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;starlite.png&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osaka&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;small-block-grid-2 medium-block-grid-3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;th&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;osaka-blue.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;osaka-blue.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;th&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;osaka-green.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;osaka-green.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a class=&quot;th&quot; role=&quot;button&quot; href=&quot;osaka-brown.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;osaka-brown.png&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
                <link>/wallpaper/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/wallpaper/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2013</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0140258396/&quot;&gt;Simplicity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Edward De Bono (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
(re-read Oct 2013) What a great book. Simplicity is not a natural outcome --
you have to choose it as a value, and actively seek to achieve it. I was very
inspired by this book years ago when I first read it, and it was neat to see
how many of the ideas I repeat all the time to others (without remembering
that this book was the original source).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0465046746/&quot;&gt;Mindstorms: Children, Computers, And Powerful
Ideas&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Seymour Papert (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. The
philosophy behind the LOGO programming language as a method for teaching
mathematical thought to children -- I remember doing some of these exercises
in Grade 3 or 4. Look up Bret Victor to see some very interesting contemporary
programming tools/UI inspired by this work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0802119921/&quot;&gt;What It is Like to Go to War&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Karl Marlantes (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/019921896X/&quot;&gt;Staying Power&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Michael A. Cusumano
(4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. An excellent perspective on the qualities it takes to stay relevant in
business: &lt;br/&gt;1. platforms (not just products), &lt;br/&gt;2. services (not just
platforms or products),&lt;br/&gt;3. capabilities (not just strategy),&lt;br/&gt;4. pull
systems (not push), &lt;br/&gt;5. economies of scope (not scale),&lt;br/&gt;6. flexibility
in operations and decision making.&lt;br/&gt;This definitely gave me a new
vocabulary and lens to look at the maneuverings of giants like Sony, Apple,
IBM, ...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B005WUE6Q2/&quot;&gt;The Making of Prince of Persia&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Jordan Mechner
(4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Good times in computer history! When game development was small enough
to be done by a single person + a little help (Fred Brooks&amp;#39; surgical team?).
Also a couple of neat connections in this book for me: years ago I had read
his brother&amp;#39;s account of studying Go in Japan, and he also mentions Janice
Kim, author of the first Go book I ever read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/039915843X/&quot;&gt;Distrust That Particular Flavor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by
William Gibson (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Great stuff. Interesting to read the bits that are old
enough to feel slightly quaint, even though they are so recent (early
Internet, ebay, etc). I like collections of essays because you can jump in and
read these bite-sized pieces that are still complete thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1597269719/&quot;&gt;Human Transit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Jarrett Walker (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
I thought I already had a clear picture of the options for transit, but this
book did a great job of laying out the terms and tradeoffs really clearly, and
I can see a number of the choices in Vancouver much better now. Our city is
doing a pretty good job... it would be nice if all the debates could be so
rational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0316491977/&quot;&gt;The Soul of a New Machine&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Tracy
Kidder (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Really interesting to read about the history of the industry,
but also depressing to see all the same bullshit (schedule-chicken, resource
battles, etc) that hasn&amp;#39;t changed in 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0451524934/&quot;&gt;1984&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George Orwell (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0141035811/&quot;&gt;Design As Art&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Bruno Munari (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. A
collection of essays on state of design, and the place of art, in modern
(1966?) society. He has a bit of cultural-envy for the Japanese, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0140194614/&quot;&gt;Myths to Live By&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Joseph Campbell
(4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Myths provide symbols, patterns and conditioning for relating to your
(cultural) world, and everyone is telling some variation of the same basic
mythology. The problem with modern religion is that it&amp;#39;s trying to teach an
outmoded set of symbols. Also, kitten vs monkey cultures (other- vs self-
reliant). Great framing of some cultural differences for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/006000942X/&quot;&gt;How to Read Literature Like a Professor&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;by Thomas C. Foster (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. A nice primer on to look for when interpreting
writing. No big surprises, but a good set of triggers that would alert you to
look deeper (eg, weather, mythology, bible).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0224094157/&quot;&gt;The Sense of an Ending&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Julian Barnes (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0679778314/&quot;&gt;The Inner Game of Tennis&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by W. Timothy Gallwey (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1935182625/&quot;&gt;Generative Art&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Matt Pearson (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/B00G9FGHFW/&quot;&gt;Human JavaScript&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Henrik Joreteg (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. It was
OK. Quite a short overview of some JS modules for front-end development.
Probably aimed at junior devs, or people who haven&amp;#39;t really worked with MVC-
style frameworks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1596063173/&quot;&gt;The Lifecycle of Software Objects&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ted Chiang (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0374530491/&quot;&gt;Palm-of-the-Hand Stories&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Yasunari
Kawabata (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.  A handful of gems in there, but lots of stories that I just
got nothing from. I wonder how much of this is in the translation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/1408154161/&quot;&gt;Fast Handling Technique&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Frank
Bethwaite (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.  Repetitive and poorly edited. There&amp;#39;s still some good
information in here about setup and target speeds, but 1/3 of the book is
devoted to telling you how NOT to sail (the &amp;quot;natural handling&amp;quot; technique), and
it keeps repeating the same instructions for &amp;quot;fast handling&amp;quot; technique so I
was left puzzling about what was different in each case (nothing?). Not up to
the high standard of his other books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/159420229X/&quot;&gt;Moonwalking with Einstein: The Art and Science of Remembering Everything&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Joshua Foer (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
A lightweight version of Oliver Sacks?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/142007573X/&quot;&gt;Visualizing Data Patterns with Micromaps&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;em&gt;by Daniel B. Carr (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.  I actually found many of the map visualizations
hard to comprehend -- series of maps showing per-year values, plus a second
row of maps showing the deltas between years is too noisy and requires too
much refocusing. But, they do mention that in their testing they find some
people prefer this, while others prefer interactive flipping between frames.
What I did love was the amount of references to other research material, and
to general concerns about cognition, perception and interpretation of
visualizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0062041266/&quot;&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Patrick deWitt (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0312427808/&quot;&gt;The Housekeeper and the Professor&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by
Yōko Ogawa (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. A very simple story, told in the Japanese style of &amp;quot;being
there&amp;quot;. I don&amp;#39;t see what people find so interesting about it -- maybe romantic
ideas about mathematical intuition? Or personal experience with caring for
someone with dementia?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0691122946/&quot;&gt;On Bullshit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Harry G. Frankfurt (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
I suspect the author has a talent for bullshit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0975579983/&quot;&gt;Dead Men Scare Me Stupid&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by John
Swartzwelder (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. More Frank Burly zaniness, this time with ghosts. Just
lots of chuckles, nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/031242969X/&quot;&gt;The Friends of Eddie Coyle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George V. Higgins (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0446691437/&quot;&gt;The War of Art: Break Through the Blocks &amp;amp; Win Your Inner Creative Battles&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Steven Pressfield (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;.
Creative motivation for people who believe in God? Meh. It had a few good
moments, but in general the personification and externalization of Resistance
didn&amp;#39;t work for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0613300912/&quot;&gt;Picture This: How Pictures Work&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Molly
Bang (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Kind of interesting; short and simple. I&amp;#39;m not sure how much of
this requires cultural learning of how to interpret the symbols of a picture
(not that this takes anything away from it). Could be a good jumping off point
to go and read more deeply about the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://amazon.com/dp/0345457714/&quot;&gt;Broken Angels (Takeshi Kovacs, #2)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by
Richard K. Morgan (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;. Weak. The earlier book, Altered Carbon, was a good
matrix-meets-blade-runner blend of sci-fi and detective story. This one took
the space-marine angle, and didn&amp;#39;t really do anything interesting with it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 14:05:58 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2013/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2013/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2012</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Here we go again...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B003JBI2WU/&quot;&gt;Medium Raw&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Anthony Bourdain (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
War-stories from the kitchen. A much more mature rant than some of his earlier
writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B0042X9MGY/&quot;&gt;A Thousand Dreams&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Larry Campbell (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
The writing is a bit dry, but the insight on some contemporary Vancouver
history (which I only knew in general terms) was great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002RI9J2I/&quot;&gt;Flashman&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George MacDonald Fraser (5/5 - re-read)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Flashy, you delightful cad! Enjoyed it as much as the first time I read it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0393072959/&quot;&gt;The Wallstreet Journal Guide to Information Graphics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Dona M Wong (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A great basic reference for visual literacy and data presentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B003T0GBOM/&quot;&gt;Blindness&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by José Saramago (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002RI91PS/&quot;&gt;An Artist of the Floating World&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kazuo Ishiguro (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Subtle, but that carried me along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00403MNSK/&quot;&gt;Beer is Proof God Loves Us&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Charles Bamforth (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0883857006/&quot;&gt;Proofs Without Words&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Roger B. Nelsen (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B002EF2AE8/&quot;&gt;The Cluetrain Manifesto&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Christopher Locke et al. (4/5 re-read)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Interesting to re-read this 10 years later. Some of it is totally prescient,
and some seems fairly naive. A little too much romanticizing of craft
traditions, and nostalgia for &amp;quot;the old ways&amp;quot;, but it captures the changes of
the Net pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Game-Ken-Dryden/dp/0470835842/&quot;&gt;The Game&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ken Dryden (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Old-Mans-War-John-Scalzi/dp/0765348276/&quot;&gt;Old Man&amp;#39;s War&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by John Scalzi (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Standard space-marine fluff. Not really my kind of sci-fi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Time-Machine-Did-John-Swartzwelder-ebook/dp/B004P1JTM0/&quot;&gt;The Time Machine Did It&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by John Swartzwelder (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Absurd stream-of-consciousness by the most prolific Simpsons writer. Some
awesome moments in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/How-Wrap-Five-Eggs-Traditional/dp/1590306198/&quot;&gt;How to Wrap Five Eggs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Hideyuki Oka (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A few interesting packages, but would have be nice to have the description of
the contents closer than the appendix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Steal-Like-Artist-Things-Creative/dp/0761169253/&quot;&gt;Steal Like an Artist&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Austin Kleon (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A nice compact reminder to keep moving. I love the idea of exploring your
creative family tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Damn-Good-Advice-People-Talent/dp/0714863483/&quot;&gt;Damn Good Advice (For People with Talent!)&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George Lois (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Rapid-fire advice and autobiography from an iconic ad man -- the original Mad
Man (a show he hates)_. You definitely know his work even if you don&amp;#39;t recognize
his name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Code-Woosters-Jeeves-Wooster-ebook/dp/B0031RS7A4/&quot;&gt;The Code of the Woosters&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by P.G. Wodehouse (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Wonderful in places and wonderfully dull overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Man-Descending-Guy-Vanderhaeghe-ebook/dp/B004GTLVGS/&quot;&gt;Man Descending&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Guy Vanderhaeghe (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Snow-Country-Penguin-Modern-Classics-ebook/dp/B00B0LP3U0/&quot;&gt;Snow Country&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Yasunari Kawabata (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Social-Life-Small-Urban-Spaces/dp/097063241X/&quot;&gt;The Social Life of Small Urban Spaces&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by William H. Whyte (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Really interesting material, but the format of this book (photos and long
paragraphs) makes it tough to pick out the important points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Its-Not-How-Good-Want/dp/0714843377/&quot;&gt;It&amp;#39;s Not How Good You Are, It&amp;#39;s How Good You Want to Be&lt;/a&gt;, _by Paul Arden (3/5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Worst-Journey-World-Antarctic-1910-1913-ebook/dp/B004TIKVGM/&quot;&gt;The Worst Journey in the World&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Apsley Cherry-Garrard (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
I didn&amp;#39;t survive the journey. Fascinating subject, but too laborious for me...
I&amp;#39;ll have to try again another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Curve-Time-M-Wylie-Blanchet/dp/1770500375/&quot;&gt;The Curve of Time&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by M. Wylie Blanchet (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Poetry-Handbook-Mary-Oliver/dp/0156724006/&quot;&gt;A Poetry Handbook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Mary Oliver (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A beautifully poetic explanation of the craft of writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Information-Graphics-Comprehensive-Illustrated-Reference/dp/0195135326/&quot;&gt;Information Graphics: A Comprehensive Illustrated Reference&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Robert L. Harris (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Lots of examples to pick out the details from. Doesn&amp;#39;t directly recommend any
approach over others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/The-Grammar-Graphics-Statistics-Computing/dp/0387245448/&quot;&gt;The Grammar of Graphics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Lealand Wilkinson (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A systematic algebra for describing charts and graphics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Dropping-Ashes-Buddha-Teachings-Master-ebook/dp/B005FFPMWG/&quot;&gt;Dropping Ashes on the Buddha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Seung Sahn (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A collection of koans and teaching stories from a Korean Zen master. I didn&amp;#39;t
find this as good as the collection of teaching letters to his students, &amp;quot;Only
Don&amp;#39;t Know&amp;quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Just-Enough-Software-Architecture-Risk-Driven/dp/0984618104/&quot;&gt;Just Enough Software Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by George H. Fairbanks (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
If you could read only one book about software architecture, this should be
it. It&amp;#39;s a great examination of the process of architecting, and a reminder
to always be conscious of why you&amp;#39;re using a certain approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 14:05:58 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2012/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2012/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>A reading list for Software Developers</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;There are lots of books out there about the current dominant programming
languages (or the currently hip and fashionable smaller languages). You can
find these by searching Amazon or Stackoverflow. But software development is,
for me, much more about thinking skills, design tradeoffs, and communication. 
Let me suggest some other aspects of the job that you might consider to become 
a better developer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Develop a framework for problem solving&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/4871878309/&quot;&gt;How To Solve It: A New Aspect of Mathematical Method&lt;/a&gt;, by George Polya &lt;br&gt;
This is a great set of patterns for approaching problems in a structured way.
Although intended for mathematical problems, I find that asking the same
questions can really focus my thinking on anything.  What are the knowns?
What are the unknowns? Can you find an analogous problem and solve that?
(&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/How_to_Solve_It&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0316178314/&quot;&gt;Six Thinking Hats&lt;/a&gt;, by Edward de Bono &lt;br&gt;
People working in a group typically play several roles (eg, devil&amp;#39;s advocate,
positive thinker, moderator), but they usually do it unconsciously. If we are aware
of what kind of thinking is needed at a certain moment, we can
work together in the same mode, instead of battling each other just because
we have different assumptions about what we&amp;#39;re trying to accomplish.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Learn how to communicate visually&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0393072959/&quot;&gt;The Wall Street Journal Guide to Information Graphics&lt;/a&gt;, by Dona M. Wong &lt;br&gt;
If you need to share quantitative data from tests, benchmarks, etc., it&amp;#39;s a
good idea to understand the basics of visually presenting your data. It also
helps to recognize presentations from others that are confusing or
misleading.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0521616786/&quot;&gt;The Elements of UML 2.0 Style&lt;/a&gt;, by Scott W. Ambler &lt;br&gt;
A quick and pragmatic guide to UML diagram types.  Which kind of diamond to
use on this line? When in doubt, leave it out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0262062666/&quot;&gt;101 Things I Learned in Architecture School&lt;/a&gt;, by Matthew Frederick &lt;br&gt;
You should learn how to use figure and ground in your drawings. And how 
to draw a perfect rectangle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Manage your time effectively&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0142000280/&quot;&gt;Getting Things Done: The Art of Stress-Free Productivity&lt;/a&gt;, by David Allen &lt;br&gt;
Get your TODOs out of your head and into a system where you can be certain
they will not be forgotten. Divide your time consciously between planning and
doing. Also be careful to define tasks that really are &amp;quot;do-able&amp;quot; (it&amp;#39;s common
to write todos that are subtly vague in a way that makes them tough to
complete).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/1934356506/&quot;&gt;Pomodoro Technique Illustrated&lt;/a&gt;, by Staffan Noteberg &lt;br&gt;
This is kind of like iterative development for your tasks. Work in small
batches at a sustainable pace, focus on one thing, and reflect in order to
improve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Think a bit about the problems that your manager faces. Empathize, or maybe try to help.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/159059844X/&quot;&gt;Managing Humans: Biting and Humorous Tales of a Software Engineering Manager&lt;/a&gt;, by Michael Lopp &lt;br&gt;
Most individual developers have no idea what their
manager really does, and there&amp;#39;s a cultural blind-spot of considering
anything other than coding as &amp;quot;not real work&amp;quot;. In my experience, people who
&amp;quot;get their boss&amp;#39;s job&amp;quot; are usually surprised at how much was going on that
they were being shielded from. For a dev manager, this book hits the nail
right on the head, with humour. Learn a bit about the business outside of
code, and you&amp;#39;ll be a huge benefit to your boss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Learn a vocabulary of patterns, at different levels of abstraction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321509366/&quot;&gt;Emergent Design: The Evolutionary Nature of Professional Software Development&lt;/a&gt;, by Scott Bain &lt;br&gt;
An excellent book, explaining the ways that
pressures on your software (over time) can guide your design to grow along
with the needs. Use of patterns emerge from the need, rather than being a
design goal from the start.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321127420/&quot;&gt;Patterns of Enterprise Application Architecture&lt;/a&gt;, by Martin Fowler &lt;br&gt;
Higher-level patterns at the application level.
This is an area where there seems to be a bit of a gap in software
literature, and this, along with the others in the Martin Fowler series (eg,
Enterprise Integration Patterns), is a much-needed catalog for application
developers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0321213351/&quot;&gt;Refactoring to Patterns&lt;/a&gt;, by Joshua Kerievsky &lt;br&gt;
Framing patterns as solutions to a &amp;quot;code smell&amp;quot; is
much more effective than learning them abstractly and then looking for places
to apply your new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/013476904X/&quot;&gt;Smalltalk Best Practice Patterns&lt;/a&gt;, by Kent Beck &lt;br&gt;
This is the best resource I&amp;#39;ve found for patterns
at the class and method level (eg, ExplainingMethod, DefaultValue). This was
also published with Java code under the title &amp;quot;Implementation Patterns&amp;quot;, but
somehow the Smalltalk version is much better.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Consider the history and future of your profession&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/020161622X/&quot;&gt;The Pragmatic Programmer: From Journeyman to Master&lt;/a&gt;, by Andrew Hunt and David Thomas &lt;br&gt;
Not only very practical advice, but at the same
time the philosophy and wisdom of years of experience behind that advice.
Study this and study your craft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0201733862/&quot;&gt;Software Craftsmanship: The New Imperative&lt;/a&gt;, by Pete McBreen &lt;br&gt;
Software really isn&amp;#39;t a science, so is there
anything we can learn from the craft traditions? Studying the work of
masters, working with more experienced developers as mentors, mixing
theoretical learning with practical application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/ASIN/0201835959/&quot;&gt;The Mythical Man-Month&lt;/a&gt;, by Frederick P. Brooks &lt;br&gt;
A classic, and still applicable nearly 40 years
later because it&amp;#39;s still people developing software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2012 09:56:33 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-for-software-developers/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-for-software-developers/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Reading 2011</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Well... same number of books as &lt;a href=&quot;/reading-2010/&quot;&gt;2010&lt;/a&gt;. That was an accident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0805086714&quot;&gt;What We Say Goes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Noam Chomsky (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B005Q5ONEI&quot;&gt;Eating the Dinosaur&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Chuck Klosterman (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
An odd but enjoyable collection of chapters on contemporary culture topics (eg, how American football is socialist at heart).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0140168893&quot;&gt;Looking Around&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Witold Rybczynski (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Short essays on a wide range of topics in architecture for the layman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0596808321&quot;&gt;Making Software&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Andy Oram &amp;amp; Greg Wilson (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0441788386&quot;&gt;Stranger in a Strange Land&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Robert A. Heinlen (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
I grokked it better than when I read it as a teenager, but it didn&amp;#39;t do much for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0553348973&quot;&gt;Still Life with Woodpecker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Tom Robbins (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0982167121&quot;&gt;Machine of Death&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ryan North, Matthew Bennardo, and David Malki (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Thirty-four short stories based on the premise of a machine that can accurately predict the means of your death (but often in a maddeningly ambiguous and sometimes ironic way). Lots of inescapable fates after the style of Oedipus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0743284895&quot;&gt;Chuck Klosterman IV&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Chuck Klosterman (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Another great collection of essays on pop culture previously published in SPIN, Esquire, etc. More music industry than Eating the Dinosaur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B006G89IOO&quot;&gt;My Life in France&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Julia Child (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0061096164&quot;&gt;True Love&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Robert Fulghum (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0446541478&quot;&gt;Startup Nation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Dan Senor and Saul Singer (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0142004111&quot;&gt;Walk on Water&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Michael Ruhlman (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
It&amp;#39;s absolutely incredible what is now considered routine in pediatric heart surgery, but I wonder if the total cost is really worth it? The differences in mortality between the best and worst hospitals is shocking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0345457692&quot;&gt;Altered Carbon&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Richard Morgan (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
The Matrix meets Blade Runner? But with exchangeable physical bodies (sleeves).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1419158031&quot;&gt;The Creature from Beyond Infinity&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Henry Kuttner (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Fun but very simple. Like reading a comic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0761123695&quot;&gt;The Introvert Advantage&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Marti Olsen Laney (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Lots of interesting nuggets in there for self-reflection, but very repetitive and too self-help for my liking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0345461924&quot;&gt;Six Days of War: June 1967 and the Making of the Modern Middle East&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Michael B. Oren (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/014200121X&quot;&gt;Wooden Boats&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Michael Ruhlman (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/037571894X&quot;&gt;A Wild Sheep Chase&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Haruki Murakami (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/080215185X&quot;&gt;Teach Us to Outgrow Our Madness&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kenzaburo Oe (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
I really liked &amp;quot;A Personal Matter&amp;quot;, but this collection of shorter stories seemed like a rehash of similar ideas. Or maybe they came first and I read these in reverse order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1400078776&quot;&gt;Never Let Me Go&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Kazuo Ishiguro (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0805080120&quot;&gt;The Unfolding of Language&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Guy Deutscher (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
The drivers for the incredible complexity of language boil down to: desire for more expressiveness, economy of energy, and analogy. Oh, and if you don&amp;#39;t like modern changes, remember that every generation has lamented the death of the language, and held the previous 100 years as the pinnacle. Ok, c u l8r.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0061191981&quot;&gt;Roasting in Hell&amp;#39;s Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Gordon Ramsay (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1933372699&quot;&gt;Seven-Tenths: The Sea and its Thresholds&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by James Hamilton-Paterson (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0061992704&quot;&gt;Sh*t my Dad Says&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Justin Halpern (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B004NSVE5U&quot;&gt;Bounce&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Matthew Syed (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0553382667&quot;&gt;Letters from the Hive&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Stephen Buchmann and Banning Repplier (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0452270073&quot;&gt;Regeneration&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Pat Barker (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0446670200&quot;&gt;Thick Face Black Heart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ching-Ning Chu (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Somewhat in the style of all the &amp;#39;Art of War&amp;#39; business books. It started out with a couple of great chapters, but quickly devolved into an odd Christian interpretation of the Dharma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0099565498&quot;&gt;Calling Out For You&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Karin Fossum (5/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A murder-mystery with writing as sparse as the Norwegian landscape it describes. Beautiful character development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0679775439&quot;&gt;The Wind-up Bird Chronicle&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Haruki Murakami (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
More complex plot than A Wild Sheep Chase. Some similar themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1931520720&quot;&gt;Stories of Your Life and Others&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ted Chiang (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Spiritual science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0140449701&quot;&gt;Rashomon and Seventeen Other Stories&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Ryūnosuke Akutagawa (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
A couple of gems, but the rest did nothing for me at all. I guess he gets high ratings because of his historical place in Japanese writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/0596806310&quot;&gt;Just a Geek&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Wil Wheaton (3/5)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/159102188X&quot;&gt;The Sky Is Not The Limit&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Neil deGrasse Tyson (2/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
I wanted to like this, but... meh. (Some nerd-rage on misrepresenting physics in pop-culture, etc., I couldn&amp;#39;t tell if he was serious).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/1555975771&quot;&gt;Volt: Stories&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;by Alan Heathcock (4/5)&lt;/em&gt;. 
Harsh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2011 07:16:00 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/reading-2011/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/reading-2011/</guid>
            </item>
        
            <item>
                <title>Notes from the foredeck</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/camper_volvo_bow.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(photo by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.volvooceanrace.com/en/news/5494_Local-heroes-CAMPER-storm-to-first-in-port-victory.html&quot;&gt;Ian Roman&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Foredeck thought-exercise&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of tying a necktie&lt;br&gt;
...onto someone else&lt;br&gt;
...while they are unconscious&lt;br&gt;
...lying face down, wrapped in a tarp&lt;br&gt;
...on your garage roof&lt;br&gt;
...in the rain&lt;br&gt;
...with an audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound like fun? Get on up here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sailing at the front is tough, tricky, and your mistakes are very public. I really
enjoy it. So here are some of the things I try to pay attention to... hopefully
they could help you if you&amp;#39;re learning the bow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Before the start&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set up the spin gear, double check everything.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the sail inventory, make sure you can get at the most likely sails
quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check that the spinnakers are all packed correctly, corners accessible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check the pole jaws to make sure nothing is sticking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;check that all your halyards are clear and arranged where you want them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;hoist the jib in the left track, so your first headsail change can be done on
a starboard tack. If you&amp;#39;re in a longer-distance race, consider if you&amp;#39;re going
to be on one tack for a long time, and set the jib in the appropriate track for
an easy (inside) change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Starting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you remembered your watch, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;try to get a sight on the line from both ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;have the Mast help the jib around the shrouds, so you can stay at the bow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the tacks and gybes by pulling the headsail forward along the foot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call traffic for the skipper.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call distance to the line: use number of fingers to indicate lengths,
closed-fist to indicate right on the line, wave madly if you&amp;#39;re over early.
Don&amp;#39;t try to drive the boat -- just call the distance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Upwind&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call crab pots, puffs, big waves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;help the jib around the shrouds on tacks, stay low-side to skirt as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;anticipate the favoured downwind course and confirm with the skipper what
kind of spinnaker set you&amp;#39;re going to do.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you have to change sides for the spinnaker, clip the spin gear together
and have it hauled around so you can keep weight off the bow. If you already
have the spinnaker hooked up, leave it connected and lift the bag and all the
gear around the forestay.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Spinnaker set&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Golden Rule: spin gear outside and on top of everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;set up the spin gear, attach the sheets and guys to the clews.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;put both the guy and the sheet in the jaws of the pole for the set -- this
makes the sheet less likely to catch the pole tip on the first gybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on the last port tack, hook up the halyard to the spin head, then pull enough
slack to flip the halyard behind the spreaders and lock it off. If your jib
sheets run inside the shrouds, you can hook up the head at any time in
advance, and lightly tape the halyard to the base of the shrouds so it can
pull free when you hoist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;on final approach: double, triple check that you&amp;#39;ve got clews and head rigged
correctly and all shackles are closed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when it&amp;#39;s clear you&amp;#39;re going to make the mark: pole up, open the bag or hatch
fully, help pre-guy the spinnaker, pulling both the guy and sheet through the
jaws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;skirt the jib foot in and help the spinnaker out of the bag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;jib down on deck, remove the head completely from the luff track and the
pre-feeder to avoid it interfering with the gybe (on dip-pole boats). If you
fasten the jib down with bungees, be careful not to trap the lazy spin sheet
underneath.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;leave the jib halyard at the bow so it can&amp;#39;t get trapped on the wrong side of
the pole when you&amp;#39;re ready to re-hoist the jib. If you shackle it to the tack
bar, you have the option to grind the rig forward (&amp;quot;fraculate&amp;quot;) if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remove the jib sheet that&amp;#39;s going over the pole, and shackle it to the
shrouds. Now you don&amp;#39;t have it getting in the way while gybing (dip-pole).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Dip-pole gybing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make sure there&amp;#39;s enough slack in the lazy guy before you start -- it&amp;#39;s a
bummer to come up short when you&amp;#39;re in a hurry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;remember: grab the guy with your thumb pointing towards the shackle, flip it
over when putting it in the jaws so your thumb points toward the center of
the boat (into the boat).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call &amp;quot;Made!&amp;quot; so the crew can finish the gybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;after the gybe, flip the lazy sheet on top of the jaws and spin a few wraps
around the guy (&amp;quot;cowboy it&amp;quot;) to keep everything clean for the next gybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pull enough slack in the lazy guy to be ready for your next gybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;End-for-end gybing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;take the lazy guy and jib sheet (if still connected) to the mast, keep them
over your shoulder or in the crook of your arm. Stand on the same side as the
pole, facing forward, aft of the pole; some people feel more comfortable
facing back toward the mast, but it&amp;#39;s hard to see what you&amp;#39;re doing with the
pole tip.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when the pressure comes off the pole, release the mast end and drop in the
new guy, threading the pole under the jib sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in medium air, it&amp;#39;s fine to keep the old guy in the jaws while you hook up
the new one -- it will help keep the spinnaker under control.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;in light air, trip the old guy before you release from the mast -- this helps
to keep shape in the spinnaker and keep it flying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;push the pole forward, not out, as you go to re-attach at the mast. Step
through to the other side, still facing forward so you can watch the pole and
kite.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call &amp;quot;Made!&amp;quot; so the crew can finish the gybe.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Spinnaker douse&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reset the jib to the leeward side, remember you might need to reattach the
tack on the other side of the foreguy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reattach both jib sheets. If you have a topping lift that can be split, you
can lead the lazy sheet over the pole at the mast and free it from under the
topping lift after the pole comes down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;watch out for the pole! It has a mean right-hook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;call &amp;quot;Clear to tack!&amp;quot; for the back of the boat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Spinnaker peels&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;easiest with a changing sheet -- why mess around with swapping all the gear
twice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the new halyard is the windward halyard (at the mast), your new sail needs
to go to windward of the old one. This will be an inside set (an &amp;quot;innie&amp;quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if the new halyard is the leeward halyard, your new sail needs to go to
leeward of the old one. This will be an outside set (an &amp;quot;outie&amp;quot;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For example: the spinnaker is up on the port halyard while you are sailing on
a starboard gybe. The new (starboard) halyard is on the windward side, so
your new sail will go up to windward, inside the old one -- this will be an
inside set, outside drop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;Further reading...&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more, check out the excellent book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Racing-Crew-Malcolm-McKeag/dp/1898660166&quot;&gt;Racing Crew&lt;/a&gt;,
which covers all the basics, in detail and with humour.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2011 14:40:20 -0800</pubDate>
                <link>/foredeck/</link>
                <guid isPermaLink="true">/foredeck/</guid>
            </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>